Guide to the Herbert Thoms Photographs Used in the Publication Yale Men and Landmarks in Old Connecticut
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Herbert Thoms photographs used in the publication Yale Men and Landmarks in Old Connecticut
1966-1967
RU 656
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(4 boxes)
The materials consist of photographs and illustrations used by Herbert Thoms (Yale Medical 1910) in his book Yale Men and Landmarks in Old Connecticut (1967). Included are photographs of houses in New Haven and the surrounding areas of Yale historical figures. Most of the materials in Series I are negatives. Thoms's scrapbook in Series II is composed of descriptions and photographs of memorials and gravestones of men who played important roles in Yale's history.
Thoms, Herbert, 1885-1972
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Organized in two series: I. Illustrations, Photographs, and Negatives, circa 1967; II. Scrapbook of Memorials and Gravestones.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and illustrations used by Herbert Thoms (Yale Medical 1910) in his book Yale Men and Landmarks in Old Connecticut (1967). Included are photographs of houses in New Haven and the surrounding areas of Yale historical figures. Most of the materials in Series I are negatives. Thoms's scrapbook in Series II is composed of descriptions and photographs of memorials and gravestones of men who played important roles in Yale's history.
Architecture -- Connecticut; Historic buildings -- Connecticut; Connecticut -- History -- 1775-1865; Photographs; Yale University -- History
- Illustrations, photographs, and negatives, circa 1967; Series I
  - Chapter I
    - Boulder site of Yale College (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Shaft--Clinton (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Stanton House--Clinton (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - J. Eliot House--Clinton (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - I. Gridley House--Cromwell (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chauncey House--Durham (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Goodrich House--Durham (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - James Wadsworth House--Durham (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Nathan Hale bust--East Haddam (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Nathan Hale School--East Haddam (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Elijah Parsons House--East Haddam (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Isaac Parsons House--East Haddam (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Brainerd Memorial--Haddam (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Jeremiah Hobbart House--Haddam (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - David Dudley Field House--Higganum (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Oly Ely House--Killingworth (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Elias Coe Homested--Middlefield (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Isaac Miller Homestead--Middlefield (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Samuel Mather House--Middletown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Benjamin Henshaw House--Middletown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Joseph Alsop House--Middletown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Sen. George Phillips House--Middletown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Joseph A Barratt Memorial--Middletown, 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Richard Sill House--Saybrook (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dr. Samuel Eliot House--Saybrook (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - William Tully House--Saybrook (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bushnell House--Westbrook (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Johnathan Lay House--Westbrook (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - John Devotion House--Westbrook (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Thomas Minor House--Westfield (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chapter II
    - Site of S. Russel House--Branford (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Connecticut Hall--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Abraham Pierson Statue--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Richard Mansfield House--Ansonia (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - David Humphreys House--Ansonia (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Isaac Jones (The Rutary)--Bethany (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Edward Frisbie Home--Branford (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bowden Hall--Cheshire (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bishop Jarvis House--Cheshire (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Rev. John Foot House--Cheshire (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Phillips House--Cheshire (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Sen. William Hull House--Derby (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - John Collins, Jr. House--Guilford (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Bela Hubbard House--Guilford (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Nathaniel Johnson House--Guilford (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Lot-Benton (Lyman Becker) House--Guilford (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Jared Eliot House--Guilford (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Abel Chittenden House--Guilford (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Simon Brisdol House--Hamden (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Theosophilos Scranton House--Madison (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Janna Meigs House--Madison (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Rev. John Elliott House--Madison (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - James Hough House--Meriden (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Moses Andrews House--Meriden (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Thomas Buckingham House--Milford (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Eli Ives Memorial--Timothy Dwight College, New Haven (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bushnell Blake House--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Pierpont Stokes House--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Weir House--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Pelatiah Perit House--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Silliman House--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Jared Eliot Gateway--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Noah Porter House--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Nathan Hale Statue--New Haven (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Samuel Eels House--North Branford (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Warham Williams House--Northford (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Benjamin Trumbull House--North Haven (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - The Parsonage--South Britain (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Stiles House--Southbury (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Peter Parley House--Southbury (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - The Parsonage--Southbury (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Timothy Hinman House--Southbury (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Lyman hall Memorial--Wallingford (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Col. Thaddeus Cook House--Wallingford (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Samuel Street House--Wallingford (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Thomas Darling House--Woodbridge (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Chapter III
    - Percival Homestead--Berlin (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Johnathan Miller House--Burlington (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - John Hart House--Farmington (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Eli Todd House--Farmington (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Noah Porter House--Farmington (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Johnathan Hala House--Glastonbury (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Kimberly Smith House--Glastonbury (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Gideon Hale House--Glastonbury (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - William Welles House--Glastonbury (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Samuel Talcott House--Hartford (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Samuel Clark-Bennon Upson House--Kensington (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Nathaniel Lewis House--Plantsville (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Jonathan Edwards Memorial--South Windsor (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - John Lewis House--Rocky Hill (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Eliel Williams House--Rocky Hill (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Ebenezer Grant House--South Windsor (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - President's House--South Windsor (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Watson-Bancroft House--South Windsor (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Abraham Burbank House--Suffield (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Ebenezer Gay House--Suffield (Box 2)
    - Gallaudet Statue--West Hartford (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Sophia Fowler Memorial--Guilford (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Noah Webster House--Hartford (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Robbins House--Wetherfield (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Webb House--Wetherfield (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Silas Deane House--Wetherfield (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Martin Ellsworth House--Windsor (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Oliver Ellsworth House--Windsor (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Rev. William Russell House--Windsor (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Alexander Wolcott House--Windsor (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Oliver Mather House--Windsor (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Hezekiah Chatter House--Windsor (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Chapter IV
    - Bacon Academy--Colchester (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Samuel Nott House--Franklin (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Deacon Richard Ely House--Hamburg (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Samuel Ely House--Hamburg (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Johnathan Trumbull House--Lebanon (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - War Office--Lebanon (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - William Beaumont Homestead--Lebanon (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Gov. Buckingham House--Lebanon (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Welles-Williams House--Lebanon (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Samuel Seabury Memorial--Ledyard (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - David Hale House--Lisbon (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Brockway House--Lyme (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Seldon Homestead--Lyme (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Ely House Seldon Cove--Lyme (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Seldon Warner House--Lyme (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Shaw Mansion--New London (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Nathan Hale School--New London (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Christopher Christophus House--Niantic (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Glebe House--Norwich (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Joshua and Jabez Huntington House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Jedediah Huntington House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Samuel Huntington House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Jedediah and Ebenezer Huntington House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Simon Huntington House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Daniel Lathrop House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Joshua Lathrop House--Norwichtown (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Daniel Lathrop House--Norwichtown (Box 2)
    - Matthew Griswold House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Roger Griswold House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Judge McCurdy House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Judge William Noyes House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Moses Noyes House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - William Noyes House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Noyes-Chadwick House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Samuel Mather House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - William Lord House--Old Lyme (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Dudley Woodbridge Tavern--Old Mystic (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Dennison- Noyes House--Stonington (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Henry Champion House--Westchester (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Chapter V
    - Joseph Platt Cook House--Danbury (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Robert Silliman House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Gold Selleck Silliman House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Isaac Jennings House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Thaddeus Burr House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Nathan Bulley House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - David Ogden House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - John Sturges House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Major William Silliman House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Roger Minot Sherman House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - General Elijah Abel House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Zalmon Bradley House--Fairfield (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Seth Pomeroy House--Greenfield Hill (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Gershom Hubbell--Greenfield Hill (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Jedediah Mills House--Huntington (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Judge William Edmund House--Newton (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Nathan Hale Monument--Norwalk (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - David Barlow House--Redding (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Nathaniel Bartlett House--Redding (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Gov. Luzon B. Morris House--Sandy Hook (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - President Hadley's Country House--Saybrook (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - James Earl Sheffield Hosue--Southport (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Gen. Joseph Walker House--Stratford (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - William Samuel Johnson House--Stratford (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Fairchild House--Stratford (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - David Judson House--Stratford (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Chapter VI
    - Joseph Bellamy House--Bethlehem (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Jonathan Edwards, Jr. House--Colebrook (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Gold Homestead--Cornwall (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Asaph Hall House--Goshen (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Origin Seymour House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Benjamin Tallamadge House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Timothy Dwight House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Oliver Wolcott House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Oliver Wolcott II House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Dr. Reuben Smith House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Reuben Smith Apothecary Shop--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Ephriam Kirby House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Judge James Gould House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - The Litchfield Law School (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Tapping Reeve House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Lynde Lord, Jr. House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Julius Deming House--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Lyman Beecher Memorial--Litchfield (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Dan Huntington House--New Milford (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Dr. Seth Bird House--New Milford (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - William Taylor House--New Milford (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Roger Sherman House--New Milford (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Roger Sherman House site--New Milford (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - The Parsonage--New Preston (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Giles Pettibone House--Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - William W. Welch Memorial (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Phineas Smith House--Roxbury (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Ephriam Hinman House--Roxbury (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Governor Smith House--Sharon (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Ebenezer Gay House--Sharon (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Samuel Mills Homestead--Torrington (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Dr. Samuel Woodward House--Torrington (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - The Old Parsonage--Warren (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Rev. John Trumbull House--Watertown (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - The Glebe House--Woodbury (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Chapter VII
    - Eleazar Wheelock House--Columbia (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - James Root House--Coventry (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Hale Homestead--Coventry (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Seymour House--New Haven (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Joseph Winthrop House--South Coventry (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Governor Peters House--Hebron (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Kibbe House--Somers (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Stafford Springs House--Stafford Springs (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Chapter VIII
    - Moses Cleveland Memorial--Canterbury (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Elisha Painte [Prudence Crandell] House--Canterbury (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Cogswell Homestead--Canterbury (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Mosley Homestead--Hampton (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Manasseh Cutler Memorial--Killingly (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Copp House--Killingly (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Dr. Elisha Parkins House--Plainfield (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Thomas Grosvenor House--Pomfret (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Ebenezer Devotion House--Scotland (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - David Ripley House--Abington (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Walter Lyon Homestead--Abington (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Edward Waldo House--Scotland Station (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Huntington House--Scotland (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Eliphalet Dyer House--Windham (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Jedediah Elderlen House--Windham (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - General Samuel McClellan House--South Woodstock (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Chapter IX
    - James Noyes, Jr. Memorial--Stonington (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Israel Chauncely Memorial--Stratford (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Thomas Buckingham Memorial--Saybrook (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Abraham Pierson Memorial--Clinton (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Samuel Mather Memorial--Windsor (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Samuel Andrew Memorial--Milford (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Timothy Woodbridge Memorial--Hartford (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - James Pierpont Memorial--New Haven (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Noadiah Russell Memorial--Middletown (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Joseph Webb Memorial--Fairfield (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Samuel Russel Memorial--Branford (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Moses Noyes Memorial--Old Lyme (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Thomas Ruggles Jr. and Sr. Memorial--Guilford (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Jared Eliot Memorial--Clinton (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Elisha Williams Memorial--Wethersfield (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Phineas Fiske Memorial--Haddam (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - John Hart Memorial--Madison [East River] (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Samuel Russell, Jr. Memorial--North Guilford (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Jacob Hemingway Memorial--East Haven (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Nathaniel Chauncey Memorial--Durham (Box 3, Folder 157)
- Scrapbook of memorials and gravestones, Series II
  - Introduction (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abraham Pierson, 1645-1707 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - James Noyes, Jr., 1634-1719 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Israel Chauncey, 1644-1703 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Buckingham, ?-1709 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Samuel Mather, 1651-1728 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Samuel Andrew, 1656-1738 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Timothy Woodbridge, ?-1732 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - James Pierpont, 1660-1714 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Noadiah Russell, 1659-1713 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Joseph Webb, 1666-1732 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Samuel Russell, 1660-1731 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Moses Noyes, 1643-1729 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Thomas Ruggles, Sr., 1671-1728 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Ruggles, Jr., 1704-1770 (Box 1)
  - Elisha Williams, 1694-1755 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Jacob Hemingway, 1683-1754 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Nathaniel Chauncey, 1681-1756 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - John Hart, 1682-1731 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Phineas Fiske, 1682-1738 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jared Eliot, 1685-1763 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Samuel Russell, Jr., 1693-1746 (Box 1, Folder 21)